"Fortune favors the bold."
Virgil, "Aeneid"
Quit spreading these
shitty rumors, Hashimoto!
We know you're the one spreading
this crap on Sakayanagi's orders.
Please, stop it, Ibuki-san.
You stay out of this!
We're not gonna let this stand, man.
You really want to do this?
Hey, don't!
Stop it!
You back off! It's none of your business!
Ayanokoji got rumors spread about him, too.
It is our business.
A little crush on Karuizawa's
barely anything, though.
I-It is not!
I don't like to say this,
but I suspect you, as well, Hashimoto.
Yeah, I'll bet.
I'm the only witness to your secret
meet-up with Karuizawa, after all.
Meet-up?!
It was nothing serious.
Don't ignore us, you bastard!
Ishizaki-kun, please don't fight!
But...
Even if you get him to confess,
Sakayanagi-san will never admit to it.
So we're just supposed
to lie down and take it?!
Could I ask you to forgive them for today?
Nothing to forgive.
There's no real harm done.
But I'd appreciate it if you'd
stop suspecting us for no reason.
We don't need baseless
accusations in our lives.
Understood.
Let's go.
Ichinose-san finally came to school, did she?
Just in time for finals.
What's our next move?
Okay.
You all did great.
You got a 90, Kiyo-pon? That's awesome!
You all did about as well.
Hey!
Some people from Class A
just barged into Class B!
What do you want, Sakayanagi-san?
I've always had such respect
for the teamwork of Class B.
What are you getting at?
I've come here to save you.
Why don't you get to the point already?
You've entrusted all your private
points to Ichinose-san,
and backed by that savings,
you've overcome many hardships.
It's in regard to that.
What about it?
There's nothing wrong with it, in and of itself.
But what if it turns out that
this accusation is true?
What if Ichinose-san really is a criminal?
It's nonsense.
Just like the other rumors
you've been spreading.
I'm sure I have no idea
what you're talking about.
What I'm holding is solid proof
that the rumors about Ichinose-san are true.
She's got proof?
What could it mean?
Calm down, everyone!
To entrust the entire class's
points to someone like that...
It just seems self-destructive, doesn't it?
Is anything I'm saying false,
Ichinose Honami-san?
Could you please let me through?
Ichinose?
It'll be fine.
I'm sorry, everyone.
Be very quiet, everyone.
She's attempting to show contrition.
Everyone...
Would you be willing to
hear what I have to say?
Sakayanagi-san is right.
I have committed a crime.
An unforgivable crime.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
Four Years Ago
I lived with just my mother
and my little sister.
It wasn't a life of luxury,
but we had a lot of fun.
Our mother worked very,
very hard to provide for us.
One Year Ago
So I ran full tilt to earn scholarships
to get into high school,
3rd-Year  Mock Exam  Extraordinary Scores
1st  Ichinose Honami
2nd  Tanaka Yusuke
even though I didn't have the money.
But...
In the summer of my third
year of middle school...
My mother...
collapsed.
Emergency Exit
It turned out that, in trying to buy
a birthday present for my sister,
she took on more shifts
than she could handle.
My sister loved this one idol girl...
And she had this one hair clip.
My sister never talked about wanting
fashionable clothing or games.
It was the first thing
she'd ever said she wanted.
Mom apologized over and over again.
"I'm sorry I couldn't give
you a birthday present."
So I made up my mind.
I would buy that hair clip
for my little sister.
I knew it was coming,
but obviously, no one was willing to
hire a middle school student part-time.
Work Days
Days Off
Salary
2-5 per week
Days Off
General 1,200 yen
High School 1,080 yen
*Cannot hire middle school
Nevertheless, I did everything
I could to earn money.
Except...
Last Chance to Buy
Wow! Isn't it so cute?
It's the one she wore in the magazine!
Yeah! I've wanted it so much!
I love it!
Hey, let's come back tomorrow!
Yeah! We can't afford it today,
but if we come back tomorrow...
Last Chance to Buy
I wanted that hair clip so badly.
Nobody saw me.
I lied and said a friend lent me the money.
My sister was so happy.
She said, "Thanks, Big Sis!" so many times.
The sight of my sister's smile
temporarily alleviated my guilt.
When my mother got out of the hospital,
my sister and I went to see her.
My sister was so proud as she
showed our mother the hair clip.
I couldn't bring myself to tell
her to keep it a secret...
She was just so happy about it!
I think my mother knew I'd stolen it.
I couldn't hide it.
She quickly took me back to the
store to make me apologize.
I was finally coming to terms
with exactly what I'd done.
The minute we got home, my mother started
crying, like a dam had burst inside her.
I'd never seen my mother
cry like that before.
In the end, the people from the store
didn't turn me in to the police.
I completely withdrew.
I spent six months rebuking myself.
I didn't leave my room.
But...
My mother told me...
Don't give up on high school.
"Honami, don't give up on high school."
"I want you to find your own happiness."
So when I came here,
I decided to try for a fresh start.
To restore my mother's and
sister's trust in me, too.
Everyone...
I'm so sorry I never told you.
I'm sorry I've been such an awful leader.
You're not, Ichinose!
We understand what you were going through.
You shared your secret with us
now because you trust us, right?
You guys...
Are you trying to make me laugh?
Sakayanagi-san...
No matter the circumstances,
shoplifting is shoplifting.
There's nothing to feel sympathy for.
Yes. You're right.
The sins you've committed
never fully go away.
Ichinose...
It's true. I shoplifted.
I don't intend to run away from that.
Because... I did do something wrong.
Such a brazen lack of shame.
You're right.
Perhaps all my hard work came
from a place of pretend virtue.
But... I want to graduate with
all of you. In this class!
I want to walk alongside all of you!
Despite all my failings, everyone...
Will you come to the very end with me?
Of course we will.
We'll come along with her, right?
You bet!
Yeah!
Of course!
That's amazing.
Sakayanagi. What now?
Hey, come on!
I see.
Isn't this a happy little resolution?
But the truth remains that
you committed a crime.
The story's going to continue to spread.
I'm prepared for that.
Are you?
Then I'll do—
Okay, that's enough.
The student council president
and the teachers?
The spreading of malicious
rumors is hereby forbidden.
Did Ichinose-san report the
trouble she was having?
This problem has gone far
beyond just Ichinose.
We've been made aware of
the hurtful comments being
perpetuated among you first-years.
Any further spreading of rumors would
breach the school's code of morality.
Any person found spreading malicious
rumors will henceforth be punished.
I see.
If the school's gotten involved,
then my business here is finished.
I'll be taking my leave.
Splendidly done, Ayanokoji-kun.
Could you tell me one thing?
Did Ichinose-san confess her
past to you before today?
Yes.
I visited Ichinose's room yesterday.
Hey... could I ask you a strange question?
Sure.
Why don't you say anything to me?
The reason I come here every day
is because I'm waiting for you to confess...
I suppose.
Waiting for me... to confess?
I know what crime it is you're guilty of.
Ichinose.
What you did won't vanish
because you ran from it.
Stop it!
I... I just...
I know I did a bad thing.
I really thought I didn't have a choice!
I wanted to make my sister smile!
I was so thoughtless.
I was so stupid.
Running was all I could do.
And now, again...
And now, just like then,
I've completely withdrawn.
What should I have done?
What should I do now?
Tell me.
Tell me, Ayanokoji-kun!
How am I supposed to leave this room?
I don't know.
I think you'll just have to face it yourself.
Am I wrong?
Ichinose's heart was broken.
I'm...
I'm the one
who shattered it.
Then the broken part healed
back stronger than before,
allowing her to rebuke your accusation.
That's what happened.
How very moving.
You used Kamuro to bring
me into this, didn't you?
What makes you so sure?
The can of beer she gave me is the one
she stole early in the school year.
The "best by" date on the can she gave me
was almost a year before
the ones currently on sale.
Which means that beer came
from you, Sakayanagi.
I'd initially intended to simply
wait and watch what happened.
But you used Kamuro to drag me into it.
Why?
I did it all to get you interested in me.
So you don't care about Ichinose at all?
Correct.
Why don't we have a competition?
I don't see what I have to gain by agreeing.
What if I put my own expulsion on the line?
Obviously, even if I lose,
you won't need to quit school yourself.
However...
If you lose, I will reveal to everyone
that you're the mastermind behind Class C.
What are we wagering on?
How about the upcoming exam?
It seems my school life is
finally about to get exciting.
Thank you for the chocolate you gave me.
I didn't call you here to
talk about that, silly.
The information Kushida gave me
before Valentine's was on the money.
Vice President Kiriyama, I want you to post
this information on the message boards.
To save Ichinose.
If this comes out, trust among
the student body will plummet.
The person who will be hurt the
most by that is President Nagumo.
Wouldn't that be to your benefit?
And I'll be the one punished for it.
If you refuse to do this,
I'll have to report to the former president
that you've already fallen
in line with Nagumo.
Very well.
You owe me a big favor, though.
I appreciate it.
I'm just happy to be of service!
So, you know what to do, right?
Yeah.
Points will be transferred.
Accept?
Cancel  Confirm
I just sent you your informant's fee.
Point Transfer in Progress
Go on and check it.
Looks great to me!
From now on, I'll be giving you
half of any points that I earn.
Is that acceptable?
Yep!
As long as you keep paying me,
I'll let bygones be bygones.
You're so smart, Ayanokoji-kun.
You're not at all like Horikita-san.
Can we continue to get along?
Rising to Sakayanagi's challenge
and saving Ichinose were purely incidental.
There's only one thing I wanted
to learn via this incident...
The quality and quantity of the
information Kushida Kikyo possesses.
To confirm that,
and to compel her expulsion.
Morning, Ayanokoji-kun!
Morning.
You were pretty cool yesterday.
Y-You think so?
It's impressive to put your old
demons to rest with your own power.
Yeah, I guess.
I can't take back what I did back then.
But...
I think I can live with it from now on.
If you ever run the risk of
losing sight of yourself again,
feel free to talk to me.
I'm always capable of listening, at least.
You'd let me rely on you like that?
If you're willing to, at least.
I... I see.
Um, I...
What is it?
Well, see...
Oh, th-that's funny...
I thought it would come out more smoothly.
What's wrong with me?
I've never given anyone
something like this before...
But I'm not sure how else to
show my appreciation, so...
You don't have to force it.
I-I-I-I'm not forcing it!
It's a bit late... but here.
Valentine's Day chocolate.
Y-You don't want it?
I do.
Thank you.